Ali Ataf

Frontend Developer

A Software Engineer with over 2 years of experience in frontend development with a passion for building and maintaining responsive, accessible, and performant websites. I have worked with technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Vue, Next.js and Tailwindcss.

aliattaf98@gmail.com

+971 050 235 7409

Sharjah, UAE

www.aliataf.me

linkedin.com/in/ali-ataf

ne 🖫

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Nestech 🗷

09/2021 - Present

Svria (Remote)

- Worked directly with UI/UX designer and converted the designs she gave me to fast front-end web applications.
- Engaged in daily scrum meetings with our five members team to optimize the development process.
- Finished 5+ web applications with a responsive mobilefirst approach from concept to deployment.

Frontend Developer

BadinanSoft 🗷

04/2021 - 09/2021

Iraq (Remote)

- Established testing and modular coding development environment for company projects.
- Enhanced legacy projects UX by implementing the right technologies and fixing UI bugs.
- Helped the project manager to organize the team's tasks using Jira software.

Frontend Developer

Unifi Solutions 🗷

11/2020 - 04/2021

Montreal, QC (Remote)

- Led the development process of the "BACT" system.
- Automated the injecting of state and routing modules using JS scripts.
- Maintained scalable system-wide components that were used in the IoT web application.

Junior Frontend Developer

Zeuor 🗷

09/2019 - 11/2020

Suria

- Built web applications for Queue Management System.
- Reduced load time by over 60% by dropping jQuery UI and re-writing all CSS from scratch.
- Implemented visual designs that are user-friendly.

EDUCATION

Master of Web Science Syrian Virtual University

01/2022 - Present

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Tishreen University

09/2016 - 09/2021 (GPA: 3.4 / 4.0)

SKILLS



PROJECTS

Tasgment (09/2020 - 09/2021) 🗹

- Transformed the design of the application into a well-structured web application.
- Implemented SSO, 2fa, and chat system in the project.
- Deployed the app on digitalocean droplet and set the server up dealing with all related server issues.
- Stack: Vue.js, Element UI, Vuex, SortableJS, PHP, Laravel, Dart, Flutter, Firebase, Pusher.

DisruptX IoT (01/2021 - 04/2021) 🗗

- Developed responsive email templates across various email clients using table layout and inline styles.
- Participated in the system structure decisions and contributed to the modular structure used in the application.
- Worked closely with designers and product owners to translate clients' requirements into scalable web applications.
- Stack: Vue.is, Quasar, Vuex, Node.is, Express.

BACT learning system (11/2020 - 01/2021) 🗗

- Designed, analyzed, and broke down the requirements into categorized tasks with priorities.
- Handled all requirements changes working in an agile methodology.
- Translated designs into reusable UI components.
- Stack: Vue.js, Vuetify, Vuex.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Won 3rd place in Tamayuz competition

Participated in the "Encouraging Arabic content to use digital transformation tools" category.

LANGUAGES

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Arabic

English

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Chess Reading

Music